It was an age of war.
Relying on only his own skill,
one man wandered the land.
A samurai.
This man is not
a wandering samurai of today.
It's expensive.
-Hey!
-How is it? How is it?
It's just dinner with my niece.
My clothes don't matter.
That's not true.
It'd be embarrassing if a man of
your age came dressed in shabby clothes.
Now, try this on.
What a pain.
Don't say that.
Thank you.
Good!
Be sure to decide where
to take Masako for dinner.
I can't go. I've got choir practice.
Huh? I'm going by myself?
That's right.
I got a call from my brother last night.
Masako's been saying
she isn't getting a job
even though she graduates soon.
It sounds like it's been difficult.
Masako? Really?
Yes.
So, be sure to give her
some advice as her wise uncle.
That's not really my thing.
She won't listen to her parents.
Why would she listen to me?
You're perfect for the job.
-Why?
-You're her uncle.
TOP RESTAURANTS
FRENCH CUISINE
Maybe a little too fancy.
JAPANESE CUISINE
TASAKI SUSHI
Sushi?
Probably expensive.
BBQ & YAKINIKU
Steak?
Steak sounds good!
You startled me.
Don't you know any good restaurants?
Well,
there is a place my boss took me once.
How about going there?
But young people don't go there.
So what?
As long as the food is good.
True.
I wonder where I put that phone number.
By the way...
don't drink too much
in front of Masako, okay?
Promise?
I know.
After retiring,
he lost his title as a corporate man
and the support of his company.
Takeshi Kasumi, 60 years old.
This story
is about a normal 60-year-old man,
who is helped by a masterless samurai,
eating freely without being held back.
A gourmet fantasy.
YAKINIKU HER WAY
Uncle Takeshi!
Masako?
It's been so long.
Wow! You've grown.
Well, I am 21 now.
A full-grown adult!
So, where are you taking me tonight?
I was thinking yakiniku.
All right!
I'm glad I worked up an appetite.
This way.
Let's go!
All right. We're off to a good start.
YAKINIKU
KOEI
Is this your favorite place?
When I was working,
my boss brought me here once.
The food is great.
Yakiniku is best at a place like this.
Here's your food. Thank you for waiting.
Thank you!
Welcome!
I have a reservation under Kasumi.
Right this way.
Hot towels!
Yes.
Welcome.
Thank you.
Three-point-one stars online.
So-so, I guess.
Online reviews aren't everything.
Drinks?
What do you want?
Orange juice?
-Oolong tea?
-Beer, please.
What?
I'm old enough to drink now.
Two beers, right?
No, I'm fine.
Did Aunt Shizuko tell you
not to drink tonight?
-How'd you know?
-You should have at least one.
Two beers, please.
Okay, two beers.
-Can I order?
-Sure! Whatever you like!
Okay, I'll have...
the salted beef tongue.
-And the sirloin.
-Okay.
Also, the...
-mixed meat plate.
-Okay.
What kind of seasoning for the sirloin?
The house sauce.
And what is the zabuton?
It's the meat just below the shoulder.
It's well-marbled and very good.
-Then that, too, please.
-Okay.
What about you, Uncle?
Let's see...
Also, kimchi and namul.
-Okay.
-That's all.
-One moment, please.
-Okay.
This isn't good.
She's taken control.
Pardon me, here you are.
Here it is!
Coming behind you!
Here you are.
-Gukbap soup.
-Looks delicious.
And...
Korean-style rice.
Ah... Korean-style rice.
And... gukbap soup.
They both look amazing.
Here's your beer.
And with that...
-Cheers!
That's good.
I can't believe I get to have
a beer with you, Masako.
You're being silly.
Here you are.
Salted beef tongue.
Sirloin.
Namul.
Kimchi.
Here are the tongs.
-Grill the tongue first.
-Okay.
Let's get cooking.
Wait.
Here...
Uncle...
would you move that plate forward a bit?
-Sure.
-Great.
Okay, perfect. Hold on.
Kimchi!
Can we start now?
Yeah. Let's eat.
All right! Let's start!
-What?
-Well, she said to grill this first.
It doesn't really matter.
I guess not.
-Here, use these.
-Chopsticks work.
Okay.
All right.
Enjoy your meal.
Enjoy.
Delicious.
It's good.
It melts in my mouth.
Yum. Let's grill more.
All clumped together...
It's a bit sloppy.
Masako...
What now?
Grilling one at a time is--
I'm hungry and I don't want
to sit around waiting!
I want to eat it all at once.
Okay.
She has changed quite a bit.
It's about done.
There.
She is on her phone again.
What? Aren't you eating?
I'm a little busy. You go ahead.
I'm sending my band a text
about tomorrow's gig.
Band?
Ah, so that explains the guitar.
Yeah. We had a studio practice.
It sounds serious.
Well, I want to go pro.
That's why you don't want a job.
Yup.
But Dad keeps telling me to get a job.
You should say something, Uncle!
Tell him not to interfere.
I know how your dad feels.
How so?
Well, it's hard to make a living
as a musician.
Uncle, were you a pro musician?
No, but...
Then how would you know
if it's hard or not?
True, if you put it that way.
I...
don't want to have
a boring life like Dad.
That's harsh.
That was delicious.
I'm stuffed.
I'm going to burst.
That was good.
I'll be right with you.
That's done.
Oh, oops!
Here is the assorted meat platter.
There it is.
Another beer, please.
Also, some ribs.
Shouldn't you slow down a bit?
I'm fine.
I'm not a lightweight.
-Here.
-Okay, so beer
and ribs it is.
Dig in.
It looks so juicy and delicious!
Grilled to perfection and--
It's so tender! Yum!
I was grilling that for me.
Uncle...
how did you stay
at the same company so long?
Waking up at the same time every day,
taking the same train
to the same office,
working late with the same people?
I'd quit in a week.
I...
thought of quitting.
I'll never forget it.
It was my third year there.
Boss.
LETTER OF RESIGNATION
Kasumi,
you want to quit?
Yes.
I'm not motivated by this work.
That's your reason?
I'm serious.
Understood.
Let's grab dinner.
Are you ready to go?
Yes.
Okay, let's go.
-I'll get my stuff.
-Okay.
That's when my boss...
first brought me here.
-Welcome.
-For two please.
Two? Okay, over there.
Thanks.
Really?
So, what happened?
You're burning it.
Oh, sorry!
-Pay attention. This is good meat.
-Yes.
-Eat while it's hot.
-Okay.
Thank you.
You'll never get the table
clean like that!
Put your back into it.
Yeah, yeah.
Don't "yeah, yeah" me.
Here you go.
A little strict, huh?
That's all right. Now eat up.
Thank you.
Delicious.
He orders the meat,
cuts it just right and serves it.
It may be a simple job,
but it tastes good, thanks to him.
See all the grease?
Press hard and pull.
Kasumi...
motivation will come naturally
when you take ownership in your work.
It's still too soon to quit now.
He changed your mind that easily?
Lame.
Well, I didn't have a dream like you.
Here you are, a roast cut
and a rib cut.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Oh!
Those glasses
are the same as the owner's.
He left them to me.
-Did he pass away?
-Yes.
He died of an illness
three years ago.
I'm so sorry...
He loved his work to the very end.
He was always scolding me.
Anyway, enjoy.
Let's grill some more meat.
The roast looks great!
Amazing!
Masako, you're not eating.
-It's delicious.
-In a minute.
But if you don't, it'll get cold.
You're so annoying!
Fine, I'll eat now. Happy?
It's just...
It's just meat.
Why are grownups always
telling me what to do?
It's my life.
Let me live it how I want.
A spoiled and ignorant child.
It makes me laugh.
What is this?
Independence...
is not so easily attained.
I know that.
-That's--
-No!
You know nothing.
Hey!
What are you doing?
You're weak!
These hands haven't seen battle.
What? Battle? Let go of me! Let go!
Fine.
Jerk!
What?
To turn your back
on your parents and disrespect them
is the act of an outlaw.
If you truly want independence...
fight for it fair and square.
Earn it with your life.
Here.
Take it!
Masako...
if you truly want to be a musician...
you must first...
gain your father's consent.
Sorry.
It's not my business.
I'm a little tipsy.
I'm mad now.
So mad! It's been a while since
I've been preached to like that.
I'm sorry.
But I'm glad...
you told me face-to-face.
No one else will.
I wish you were my dad.
Excuse me! Another beer, please!
-Okay!
-Here you go.
You sure can drink!
-I'll have another one, too!
-Okay!
Tastes great!
The meat!
Here we go.
-Here, Uncle, eat up.
-Thank you.
There we are.
Really? I don't remember that at all.
Yeah, that happened.
I'll be okay from here.
I'll walk you.
No, that's okay.
-Really?
-Thank you for dinner.
Of course.
Call me if you visit again.
My wife's dying to see you.
And, Uncle...
I'll talk to my dad when I get home.
I'll explain that I am pursuing
my dream to be a musician.
That's good.
Good luck.
-Okay. Take care!
-Bye.
Take care.
Subtitle translation by
Jeffrey Hales